《星际迷航8：第一类接触》
卢丘塔斯
Locutus.
我是博格的卢丘塔斯 反抗是没有用的
I am Locutus of Borg. Resistance is futile.
授权 皮卡特4-7-α-T
Authorization, Picard 4-7-alpha-tango.
- 上将 - 打扰到你了吗 吉恩·卢克？
- Admiral. - Catch you at a bad time, Jean-Luc?
当然没有
No, of course not.
我刚从深空5号接到一个令人不安的消息
I've just received a disturbing report from Deep Space Five.
我们在艾佛星上的殖民地今天上午被摧毁了
Our colony on Ivor Prime was destroyed this morning.
- 远程传感器探测到… - 是的 我知道 博格人
- Long-range sensors have picked up… - Yes, I know. The Borg.
船长日志 星历 50893.5
Captain's Log, Stardate 50893.5.
我担心了近六年的时刻终于来临了
The moment I have dreaded for nearly six years has finally arrived.
我们的死敌 博格人 开始入侵联邦
The Borg, our most lethal enemy, have begun an invasion of the Federation,
这一次 可能没有人能拦得住他们
and this time, there may be no stopping them.
- 有多少艘船？- 一艘
- How many ships? - One.
直接冲着地球开过去
And it's on a direct course for Earth.
一小时之内就会进入联邦区域
They will cross the Federation border in less than an hour.
海耶斯上将在台风区部署了一支舰队
Admiral Hayes is mobilizing a fleet in the Typhon sector.
我们以最快的速度 只要3小时25分钟就能到…
At maximum warp, it will take us three hours, 25 minutes…
- 我们不去 - 我们不去是什么意思？
- We're not going. - What do you mean, we're not going?
我们的任务是在中立区巡逻
Our orders are to patrol the Neutral Zone.
以防止罗姆卢斯人会趁机入侵.
in case the Romulans decide to take advantage of the situation.
罗姆卢斯人？
The Romulans?
船长 在过去的九个月以来
Captain, there has been no unusual activity.
罗姆卢斯边境没有什么异常的行为
along the Romulan border for the last nine months.
他们不可能在这个时候挑起冲突
It seems highly unlikely they would choose this moment to start a conflict,
舰队是不是觉得我们应该继续适航？
Does Starfleet feel we need more shakedown time?
船长 我们在太空里待了近一年了 我们能行
Captain, we've been out in space nearly a year now. We're ready.
企业E号是舰队里最先进的星际舰船
The Enterprise-E is the most advanced starship in the fleet.
我们应该上前线
We should be on the frontline.
这些我都跟舰队指挥部说过了 他们的命令照旧
I have gone over all this with Starfleet Command. Their orders stand.
大副 设定航线前往中立区
Number One, set a course for the Neutral Zone.
- 比才？- 是柏辽兹 有什么情况？
- Bizet? - Berlioz. What do you have?
我们已经完成了中立区的第一遍扫描
We finished our first sensor sweep of the Neutral Zone.
有意思
Fascinating.
每立方米有20颗太空尘粒子
Twenty particles of space dust per cubic meter,
紫外线辐射反应52次 2级彗星一颗
fifty-two ultraviolet radiation spikes and a class-2 comet.
这些情况确实值得关注
This is certainly worthy of our attention.
船长 我们为什么要在这追彗星呢？
Captain, why are we out here chasing comets?
这么说吧 舰队对企业号
Let's just say that Starfleet has every confidence.
和它的船员是非常有信心的 他们只是信不过它的船长
in the Enterprise and her crew. They're just not sure about her captain.
他们认为一个曾经被博格人俘虏并同化的人
They believe that a man who was once captured and assimilated by the Borg.
不应该再一次跟他们碰面
should not be put in a situation where he would face them again.
如果这样做 就会在关键时刻
To do so would introduce an unstable element.
增添不稳定因素
to a critical situation.
真是可笑 正因为如此
That's ridiculous. Your experience with the Borg.
你才是指挥作战的最佳人选
makes you the perfect man to lead this fight.
海耶斯上将不这么想.
Admiral Hayes disagrees.
- 舰桥呼叫皮卡特船长 - 说吧
- Bridge to Captain Picard. - Go ahead.
我们刚刚收到舰队传来的消息 他们和博格人开战了
We've just received word from the fleet. They've engaged the Borg.
数据先生 调到舰队的频率 1486
Mr. Data, put Starfleet frequency 1-4-8-6 on audio.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
旗舰呼叫进取号 请在A-15区待命
Flagship to Endeavor, stand by to engage at grid A-15.
进入战位 挑战号和波兹曼号退到一号位
Defiant and Bozeman, fall back to mobile position one.
收到
Acknowledged.
博格方块已经进入可视范围 航线0-215 速度 曲翘九点…
We have it in visual range. A Borg cube on course 0 mark 2-1-5, speed warp…
我们是博格人 放下护盾投降吧
We are the Borg. Lower your shields and surrender your ships.
我们会吸纳你们生物和技术优越性
We will add your biological and technological distinctiveness to our own.
你们的文明将会为我们服务
Your culture will adapt to service us.
反抗是没有用的
Resistance is futile.
所有单位开火 重新调整护盾…
All units, open fire. Remodulate shield…
他们已经攻破了防线…
They've broken through the defense perimeter…
冲地球去了 追踪航线…
toward Earth. Pursuit course…
博格方块已经改变航线了 021-4
The cube is changing course. 0-2-1 mark 4.
挑战号 继续攻击
Defiant, continue to attack.
旗舰呼叫舰队指挥部 请增援
Flagship to Starfleet Command. We need reinforcements.
伤亡报告…
Casualty report is coming in…
来克星敦号旗舰上死亡96人 受伤22人
96 dead, 22 wounded on the Lexington.
霍克上尉 设定航线 前往地球
Lieutenant Hawk, set a course for Earth.
- 是 长官 - 最大曲翘速度
- Aye, sir. - Maximum warp.
我打算直接违抗上级的命令
I'm about to commit a direct violation of our orders.
如果有人反对 请现在说出来
Any of you who wish to object should do so now.
我会记到船长日志里
It will be noted in my log.
船长 我想我可以代表大家说一句话
Captain, I believe I speak for everyone here, sir, when I say.
让命令见鬼去吧
to hell with our orders.
红色警报！所有人员准备战斗！
Red alert! All hands to battle stations!
出发
Engage.
- 报告情况！- 主动力失效
- Report! - Main power is off-line.
我们已经失去了护盾 武器也用完了
We've lost shields and our weapons are gone.
也许今天是升天的好日子 全速撞击敌舰！
Perhaps today is a good day to die. Prepare for ramming speed!
长官 又来了一艘星舰
Sir, there's another starship coming in.
是企业号
It's the Enterprise.
挑战号快不行了
The Defiant's losing life support.
第三传送室 把上面的生还者传送过来
Bridge to Transporter Room 3. Beam the Defiant survivors aboard.
船长 上将的舰船被摧毁了
Captain, the Admiral's ship has been destroyed.
博格方块的情况怎么样？
What is the status of the Borg cube?
它的外壳已经受到了重创
It has sustained heavy damage to its outer hull.
但仪表显示 它还有动力
I am reading fluctuations in their power grid.
屏幕显像
Onscreen.
大副 接通舰队的通讯
Number One, open a channel to the fleet.
接通了 长官
Channel open, sir.
我是企业号的皮卡特船长 现在由我接管舰队
This is Captain Picard of the Enterprise. I'm taking command of the fleet.
把你们所有的武器 瞄准以下坐标
Target all of your weapons onto the following coordinates.
- 我一下令就开火 - 长官
- Fire on my command. - Sir.
这些坐标看上去不像是要害部位
The coordinates you have indicated do not appear to be a vital system.
相信我 数据
Trust me, Data.
舰队有回应了 他们在待命
The fleet's responded, sir. They're standing by.
开火
Fire.
- 霍克 立刻追击 出发 - 是 长官
- Mr. Hawk, pursuit course. Engage. - Aye, sir.
怎么了？
What?
我能听到他们
I can hear them.
有个病人坚持要到舰桥上来
I have a patient here who insists on coming to the Bridge.
欢迎光临企业E号 沃尔夫
Welcome aboard the Enterprise-E, Mr. Worf.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
- 挑战号呢？- 还可以打捞回来
- The Defiant? - Adrift but salvageable.
- 结实的小船 - 小船？
- Tough little ship. - Little?
沃尔夫先生 你可以帮忙作战
Mr. Worf, we could use some help at tactical.
还记得怎么用死光枪吧？
You do remember how to fire phasers?
传感器显示它正在发出时间粒子
Sensors show chronometric particles emanating from the sphere.
- 他们在制造时光旋涡 - 时光隧道
- They're creating a temporal vortex. - Time travel.
数据 报告情况
Data, report.
我们被卷入了时光旋涡
We appear to be caught in a temporal wake.
船长 地球
Captain. Earth.
大气里含有高浓度的甲烷
The atmosphere contains high concentrations of methane,
一氧化碳和氟
carbon monoxide and fluorine.
- 有生命迹象吗？- 有生命迹象 人口大概是90亿
- Life-signs? - Population, approximately 9 billion.
全是博格人
All Borg.
- 怎么会？- 他们肯定是回到了过去
- How? - They must've done it in the past.
把地球同化了 改变了历史
They went back and assimilated Earth, changed history.
如果他们改变了历史 我们怎么还在？
But if they changed history, why are we still here?
肯定是时光旋涡使我们
The temporal wake must have somehow protected us.
没有受到时间改变的影响
from the changes in the timeline.
- 长官 旋涡在减弱 - 保持航线 霍克
- Sir, the vortex is collapsing. - Hold your course, Mr. Hawk.
我们得跟着回去 补救他们造成的损失
We must follow them back, repair whatever damage they've done.
- 走吧 - 晚安 艾迪
- Come on. - Good night, Eddie.
回家去
Go home.
明天你就会后悔的
You're gonna regret this tomorrow.
你认识我这么久了 你应该知道
One of the things you should have learned about me by now.
我从来不后悔
is that I don't have regrets.
- 来吧 莉莉 再喝一杯 - 喂 喂 你喝得够多了
- Come on, Lily. One more round. - Z. Z, you had enough.
我可不想跟喝醉的飞行员上天
I'm not going up in that thing with a drunken pilot.
我要是清醒的话就不敢上天了
I sure as hell am not going up there sober.
那是什么？
What is that?
那个就是狮子座
That is the constellation Leo.
不 那个
No. That.
- 是东联！- 这么多年又回来了？
- It's an ECON! - After all these years?
赶快去凤凰号
We gotta get to the Phoenix.
去他的凤凰号吧
To hell with the Phoenix.
- 救命！救命！- 快！快跑！快！
- Help! Help! - Hurry! Move out! Move!
这边儿！泽弗兰！
This way! Zefram!
报告情况
Report.
护盾和远程传感器失灵 主动力还在
Shields are down, long-range sensors are off-line, main power's holding.
根据天体测量结果 现在是21世纪中期
According to our astrometric readings, we are in the mid-21st century.
从大气里的放射性同位素来看 我推测
From the radioactive isotopes in the atmosphere, I would estimate.
现在是第三次世界大战之后大概十年
we have arrived approximately 10 years after the Third World War.
有道理 很多大城市都被摧毁了
Makes sense. Most of the major cities have been destroyed,
只剩下极少政府 已经有6亿人丧生
very few governments left, 600 million dead.
- 毫无反抗力 - 船长
- No resistance. - Captain.
沃尔夫先生 准备量子鱼雷
Mr. Worf, quantum torpedoes.
- 准备好了 长官 - 开火
- Ready, sir. - Fire.
他们在冲地面开火 方位？
They were firing at the surface. Location?
西半球 北美大陆
Western hemisphere, North American continent.
好像是蒙大拿中部的一个发射基地
Looks like a missile complex in central Montana.
导弹基地
Missile complex.
日期呢 数据 告诉我确切的日期
The date. Data, I need to know the exact date.
现在是 2063年4月4日
April 4th, 2063.
- 4月4日 第一次接触的前一天 - 是这样的
- April 4th, the day before first contact. - Precisely.
这导弹基地肯定是
Then the missile complex must be.
泽弗兰·科克伦建造曲翘飞船的地方
where Zefram Cochrane is building his warp ship.
他们来这儿就是为了阻止第一次接触
That's what they came here to do, stop first contact.
有什么损坏 上尉？
How much damage, Lieutenant?
不清楚 远程传感器还没法用
Can't tell. Long- range sensors are still off-line.
我们得下去看看情况
We have to go down there, find out what happened.
数据 贝弗利 你们跟我来
Data, Beverly, you're with me.
叫战斗小组到3号传送室见我们
Have a security team meet us in Transporter Room 3.
电脑 准备21世纪的便服
Computer, mid-21st century civilian clothing.
大副 你守住舰桥
Number One, you have the Bridge.
看那儿
Over here.
他们都死了
They're all dead.
看看里面有没有科克伦 数据 我们去检查曲翘飞船
See if one of them is Cochrane. Data, let's go check the warp ship.
看来飞船的整体结构没有受损
The structural integrity of the missile appears to be intact,
不过机身多个部位和中间冷却器主系统
but there is significant damage to various sections of the fuselage.
受损很严重
and primary intercooler system.
企业号的电脑上应该有最初的设计图
We should have the original blueprints in the Enterprise computer.
得叫拉弗吉中校带一队人下来…
Commander La Forge will need to bring a team down here…
- 别开枪！我们是来帮你的！- 胡说！
- Hold your fire! We're here to help you! - Bullshit!
船长 我想我能去应付
Captain, I believe I can handle this.
你好啊
Greetings.
船长 这个人需要接受治疗
Captain, this woman requires medical attention.
θ射线严重中毒
Severe theta radiation poisoning.
好像是受损的节流阀发出的辐射
Radiation is coming from the damaged throttle assembly.
我们都得打预防针
We're all gonna have to be inoculated,
- 我得带她回医务室 - 医生…
- and I have to get her to Sickbay. - Doctor…
拜托 别跟我说什么规定
Please, no lectures about the Prime Directive.
我会让她一直昏迷的
I will keep her unconscious.
很好 叫瑞克中校带一个搜索队下来
Very well. Tell Commander Riker to beam down with a search party.
我们得找到科克伦
We need to find Cochrane.
克拉什呼叫企业号 两名人员直接前往医务室
Crusher to Enterprise, two to beam directly to Sickbay.
离飞船发射还有不到14个钟头了
We have less than 14 hours before this ship has to be launched.
- 皮卡特呼叫工程部 - 我是拉弗吉
- Picard to Engineering. - La Forge here.
佐迪 科克伦的飞船受到了损坏
Geordi, Cochrane's ship was damaged in the attack.
你带工程人员下来 有活要做了
Get down here with an engineering detail. We have work to do.
好的 我就来 船长
Right. I'm on my way, Captain.
A队去3号传送室集合
Alpha team, let's assemble in Transporter Room 3.
我们要到地面上去
We're heading down to the surface.
波特 我回来之前由你负责
Porter, you're gonna be in command till I get back.
- 是 长官 - 还有 波特
- Aye, sir. - And, Porter,
我走之后检查一下环境控制系统
check out the environmental controls while I'm gone.
有点太热了 好了 出发吧
It's getting a little warm in here. All right, let's go.
看上去是个不错的地方
Looks like a good spot right here.
很奇妙吧？
Isn't it amazing?
这艘飞船原来是枚核弹
This ship used to be a nuclear missile.
科克伦博士选择大规模杀伤性武器
It is an historical irony.
来开创和平纪元
that Dr. Cochrane would choose an instrument of mass destruction.
真是有讽刺意义
to inaugurate an era of peace.
这是我从小的梦想 数据
It's a boyhood fantasy, Data.
我在史密森学会见过这艘飞船不下百次
I must've seen this ship hundreds of times in the Smithsonian,
可从没触摸过它
but I was never able to touch it.
长官 这种触摸会改变您对凤凰号的认知吗？
Sir, does tactile contact alter your perception of the Phoenix?
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
对人类来说 经过触摸 你跟某件物体的联系会变得更密切
For humans, touch can connect you to an object in a very personal way,
它会更真实
make it seem more real.
可是我只感觉到钛外壳有缺陷
I am detecting imperfections in the titanium casing,
燃油汽管的温度变化
temperature variations in the fuel manifold.
我经过触摸 并没有比刚才变得更真实
It is no more real to me now than it was a moment ago.
我是不是打扰你们了？
Would you three like to be alone?
有什么发现？
What have you found out?
整个基地都找不到科克伦的踪影
There's no sign of Cochrane anywhere in the complex.
他肯定在这
He has to be here.
这艘飞船对他来说非常重要
There was nothing more important to him than this ship.
这次飞行是他的梦想
This flight, it was his dream.
船长 科克伦博士可能已经在基地的某个地方
Captain, we should consider the possibility.
遭遇袭击丧生了
that Dr. Cochrane was killed in the attack.
如果真这样 那人类的未来也就完了
If that's true, then the future may die with him.
你怎么想？
What do you think?
看来整个环境系统都失常了
It's like the entire environmental system's gone crazy.
不仅仅是工程室 这一层都是
It's not just Engineering. It's the entire deck.
可能是调节管道出了问题
Maybe it's a problem with the EPS conduits.
喂？
Hello?
- 嘿！- 你在跟我说话吗？
- Hey! - Are you talking to me?
还有别人在这儿进行维修吗？
Is there anyone else working maintenance in this section?
据我所知没有
Not that I know of.
保罗？
Paul?
保罗？你没事吧？
Paul? Are you okay in there?
船长？怎么了？
Captain? What is it?
皮卡特呼叫企业号
Picard to Enterprise.
沃尔夫 船上一切正常吗？
Mr. Worf, is everything all right up there?
是的 长官 16层的环境控制系统出了问题
Yes, sir. We are experiencing some environmental difficulties on Deck 16,
就这些
but that is all.
- 什么样的问题？- 在过去的一个小时内湿度上升了73%
- What kind of difficulties? - Humidity levels have risen 73%.
温度上到了10度
and the temperature has jumped 10 degrees in the last hour.
- 我和数据马上就回去 - 明白
- Mr. Data and I are returning to the ship. - Understood.
- 大副 你负责这里 - 是 长官
- Number One, take charge down here. - Aye, sir.
细胞膜的损伤已经修复了
Damage to her cell membranes is repaired.
她会没事的
She should be fine,
我再查一下她的脊柱组织
but I'd like to run another test on her spinal tissue.
再查查为什么这么热
And find out why it's so hot in here.
怎么回事？
Now what?
克拉什呼叫工程部
Crusher to Engineering.
克拉什呼叫舰桥
Crusher to Bridge.
沃尔夫中校 告诉我到底发生了什么事
Commander Worf, I need to know exactly what's been happening.
我们刚刚和16层失去了联系
We just lost contact with Deck 16.
通讯 内部传感器 一切
Communications, internal sensors, everything.
我正要调派安全小组过去调查
I was about to send a security team to investigate.
不！封锁16层
No! Seal off Deck 16.
派人守住所有入口
Post security teams at every access point.
- 是 长官 - 霍克
- Aye, sir. - Mr. Hawk.
传感器失灵之前
Before we lost internal sensors,
工程室里是什么样的状况
what were the exact environmental conditions in Main Engineering?
气压比正常值高出2000帕
Atmospheric pressure was two kilopascals above normal,
湿度为92% 摄氏39.1度
ninety-two percent humidity, 39.1 degrees Celsius.
摄氏39.1度
Thirty-nine-point-one degrees Celsius.
就像博格人的飞船
Like a Borg ship.
他们知道他们的飞船会被摧毁
They knew their ship was doomed. Our shields were down.
就趁我们护盾失效的时候潜入进来
Somehow they transported over here without being detected.
他们会同化企业号再同化地球
They'll assimilate the Enterprise, and then Earth.
瑞克请回答
Picard to Riker.
特遣队请回答
Enterprise to away team.
回答！
Respond!
长官 主控系统被改接进了工程室
Sir, main control is being rerouted through Main Engineering.
武器 护盾 推进力
Weapons, shields, propulsion.
数据 马上锁住主电脑
Quickly, Mr. Data! Lock out the main computer!
我已经用不规则的碎片密码锁住了主电脑
I have isolated the main computer with a fractal encryption code.
博格人不太可能破解这个密码
It is highly unlikely the Borg will be able to break it.
博格人切断了16层之外所有层的主动力
The Borg have cut primary power to all decks except 16.
博格人不会留在16层
The Borg won't stay on Deck 16.
醒醒 你没事了 醒醒 快点儿 快点儿
Wake up. You're all right. Come on. Come on. Wake up.
别紧张 冷静 你没事的！
Take it easy. Stay calm. You are all right!
听我说 看着我
Now, listen to me. Look at me.
你会没事的 照我的话做
You are gonna be fine. I need you to do as I say.
阿丽赛雅 全息程序还可以用吗？
Alyssa, is the EMH program still online?
- 应该可以 - 对 就这样
- It should be. - That's it. That's a girl.
我从没有用过这东西 电脑 启动全息程序
I swore I'd never use one of these. Computer, activate the EMH program.
请说明需要什么服务
Please state the nature of the medical emergency.
博格人马上就要冲进来了
Twenty Borg are about to break through that door.
你去分散他们的注意力 让我们离开！
We need time to get out of here. Create a diversion!
我的程序没这功能 我是医生 不是门栓
This isn't part of my program. I'm a doctor, not a doorstop.
跳个舞 讲个故事 随你便 只要给我们几秒钟时间
Well, do a dance, tell a story. I don't care. Just give us a few seconds.
星际舰队的医疗研究表明
According to Starfleet medical research,
博格人的植入器会导致严重的皮肤过敏
Borg implants can cause severe skin irritations.
也许你想来点止痛剂
Perhaps you'd like an analgesic cream?
哪边？
Which way?
我们得离开这一层 跟我来
We need to get off this deck. Follow me.
博格人首先会在工程部建立一个中心点
First thing they'll do in Engineering is establish a collective,
来控制那些个体
a central point from which they can control the hive.
问题是 如果我们在工程室使用粒子武器
The problem is, if we begin firing particle weapons in Engineering,
就可能会打中曲翘系统
there's a risk that we may hit the warp core.
我想我们应该先击破其中一个等离子冷却箱
I believe our goal should be to puncture one of the plasma coolant tanks.
- 数据？- 好主意
- Data? - Excellent idea.
有机体一碰到等离子冷却剂就会溶解
Plasma coolant will liquefy organic material on contact.
可博格人不完全是有机体
But the Borg are not entirely organic.
没错 他们有一半是电脑
True, but like all cybernetic life-forms,
可是没有了有机体他们就无法生存
they cannot survive without their organic components.
我已经下令所有的武器轮换使用
I have ordered all weapons to be set on a rotating modulation.
博格人很快就会适应 我们最多只能开12枪
The Borg will adapt quickly. We will be able to fire 12 shots at most.
还有件事
One other thing.
你们可能会碰到已经被同化的企业号船员
You may encounter Enterprise crew members.
记住 格杀勿论
who've already been assimilated. Don't hesitate to fire.
相信我 这对他们是解脱
Believe me, you'll be doing them a favor.
出发吧
Let's go.
迪安娜！迪安娜！
Deanna! Deanna!
不 不！别关掉…
No, no! Don't turn off the…
这小子是谁？
Who is this jerk?
谁叫他关掉我的音乐？
Who told him he could turn off my music?
维尔·瑞克 泽弗兰·科克伦
Will Riker, Zefram Cochrane.
- 他是你朋友？- 对
- Is he a friend of yours? - Yes.
- 你丈夫？- 不
- Husband? - No.
很好
Good.
- 这个 迪娜… - 迪安娜
- Now, this, Deena… - Deanna.
- 这个才是好货色 - 科克伦博士…
- This is the good stuff. - Dr. Cochrane…
敬凤凰号 祝它入土为安
To the Phoenix, may she rest in peace.
好吧 这酒不怎么样
Okay, that wasn't so good.
维尔 我们应该告诉他真相
Will, I think we have to tell him the truth.
- 如果说出来 那时间顺序… - 时间顺序？
- If we tell the truth, the timeline… - Timeline?
我们没时间讨论时间 我们没时间
This is no time to argue about time. We don't have the time.
- 我说什么了？- 你醉了
- What was I saying? - You're drunk.
- 你醉了！- 不 你醉了
- I am not! - Yes, you are.
听着如果我不陪他喝酒他根本就不理我
Look, he wouldn't even talk to me unless I had a drink with him.
我喝了三杯龙舌兰酒才知道
And then it took three shots of something called tequila.
他就是我们要找的人
just to find out he was the one we're looking for.
我又花了20分钟才摆脱了他的毛手毛脚
And I've spent the last 20 minutes trying to keep his hands off me.
所以别来评判我的什么谈判技巧
So don't go criticizing my counseling technique.
对不起
Sorry.
这就是原始文明？
It's a primitive culture?
- 我只是想入乡随俗 - 你做到了 很好
- I'm just trying to blend in. - You're blended, all right.
我跟他说了我们编的故事 可是他根本不信
I already told him our cover story. He didn't believe me.
我们没有时间了
We are running out of time.
如果我们告诉他 他能接受吗？
Now, if we tell him the truth, do you think he'll be able to handle it?
如果你是在询问我这个飞船顾问的专业意见
If you're looking for my professional opinion as ship's counselor,
- 他是个疯子 - 我一定会写进日志的
- he's nuts. - I'll be sure to note that in my log.
船长 我相信我感觉到了焦虑
Captain, I believe I am feeling anxiety.
一种很奇怪的感觉 让我心烦…
It is an intriguing sensation. A most distracting…
数据 这对你来说肯定很新奇
Data, I'm sure it's a fascinating experience,
不过我建议你应该把情绪芯片关掉
but perhaps you should deactivate your emotion chip for now.
好主意 长官
Good idea, sir.
好了
Done.
数据 有时候我真的很羡慕你
Data, there are times that I envy you.
是我！
It's only me!
- 医生 你没事吧？- 没事 不过有人受伤了
- Doctor, are you all right? - Yes, but we have wounded here.
洛佩兹 带他们回14层
Lopez, get these people back to Deck 14.
还有个平民 一个21世纪的女人
There was a civilian, a woman from the 21st century.
- 我们走散了 - 我们会找她
- We got separated. - We will watch for her.
沃尔夫 她不清楚状况 尽量找到她
Worf, she has no idea what's going on. Try to find her.
大家放下武器
Lower your weapons.
如果他们不认为我们是威胁 就不会离我们
They'll ignore us till they consider us a threat.
手动开关
The manual release.
沃尔夫 守住这儿
Mr. Worf, hold this position.
手动开关启动
Manual release is online.
也许我们该敲敲门
Perhaps we should just knock.
数据
Data.
死光枪准备！
Ready phasers!
数据 掩护我
Data, cover me.
船长 他们已经适应了！
Captain, they've adapted!
撤回15层 别让他们碰到你！
Regroup on Deck 15. Don't let them touch you!
- 船长！- 数据！
- Captain! - Data!
这边！
Here!
船长！
Captain!
救我！
Help!
求你 救我！
Please, help!
- 你！你怎么会… - 后退！
- You! How the hell did you… - Back off!
- 冷静点！- 闭嘴！
- Calm down! - Shut up!
- 你是谁？- 我叫吉恩·卢克·皮卡特
- Who are you? - My name is Jean-Luc Picard.
不！你们是什么人？什么组织的？
No! Who are you with? What faction?
我不是东联的人 听着…
I'm not a member of the Eastern Coalition. Listen…
闭嘴！
I said shut up!
不管你们是什么人 带我离开这
I don't care who you're with. Get me the hell out of here.
快点！
Now!
这可能不太容易
That isn't going to be easy.
你最好想个办法出来 士兵
Well, you better find a way to make it easy, soldier,
不然我可就开枪了
or I'm gonna start pushing buttons.
好吧！
All right!
- 跟我来 - 慢点走！
- Follow me. - Slow!
你们是做不到的
Your efforts to break the encryption codes.
你们是无法破解这些密码的
will not be successful.
你们也没法把我同化成你们那样
Nor will your attempts to assimilate me into your collective.
真是豪言壮语
Brave words.
在你被制造出来之前 上千个世界里的上千个物种
I've heard them before, from thousands of species.
都跟我说过同样的话
across thousands of worlds since long before you were created.
可现在 他们全都成了博格人
But now, they are all Borg.
我跟你以前碰到过的生命体不一样
I am unlike any life-form you have encountered before.
我的中枢神经网密码是不能撤除的
The codes stored in my neural net cannot be forcibly removed.
你只是一个由不完美个体制造出来的不完美个体
You are an imperfect being created by an imperfect being.
找到你的弱点只是时间问题
Finding your weakness is only a matter of time.
让我看看我是不是真搞清楚了
Let me just make sure that I understand you correctly,
中校
Commander.
一群电脑生物 从未来穿越时空
A group of cybernetic creatures from the future.
前来征服人类
have traveled back through time to enslave the human race,
- 而你们要阻止他们？- 没错
- and you're here to stop them? - That's right.
酷毙了 你们真英勇
Hot damn. You're heroic.
我们会证明给你看 佐迪！
We're gonna prove it to you. Geordi!
- 她在那儿 真漂亮！- 好吧 你自己看
- There she is. Beautiful! - Here we go.
- 好 我来看看 - 好
- All right, take a look. - Well, well, well.
看这是什么东西？
What do we got here?
我喜欢看西洋镜
I love a good peep show.
小把戏
That's a trick.
- 怎么做到的？- 望远镜是你的
- How'd you do that? - It's your telescope.
那是我们的飞船企业号
That's our ship, the Enterprise.
- 莉莉就在上面？- 没错
- And Lily's up there right now? - That's right.
我能跟她说话吗？
Can I talk to her?
不知为什么 我们失去了联系
We've lost contact with the Enterprise. We don't know why yet.
那你们要我做什么？
So, what is it you want me to do?
很简单 明天早上按原定计划进行曲翘飞行
Simple. Conduct your warp flight tomorrow morning just as you planned.
为什么明天早上？
Why tomorrow morning?
因为11点钟会有一艘外星飞船经过太阳系
Because at 11:00 an alien ship will begin passing through this solar system.
外星 你是指外星人？
Alien. You mean extraterrestrials?
- 那些坏家伙？- 好家伙
- More bad guys? - Good guys.
他们出来进行勘察 他们 对地球毫无兴趣
They're on a survey mission. They have no interest in Earth.
太落后了
Too primitive.
明天 等他们探测到飞船发出的曲翘信号
Doctor, tomorrow morning, when they detect the warp signature from your ship.
意识到人类已经知道怎样超光速飞行
And realize that humans have discovered how to travel.
他们就会改变航向
faster than light, they decide to alter their course.
来这儿跟地球进行第一次接触
They make first contact with Earth, right here.
- 这儿？- 实际上是那儿
- Here? - Actually, over there.
那是人类历史上最关键的时刻之一 博士
It is one of the pivotal moments in human history, Doctor.
你将会与外星人进行第一次接触
You get to make first contact with an alien race,
在那之后 一切都开始改变
and after you do, everything begins to change.
因为你的曲翘驱动理论 星际舰队才得以建立
Your theories on warp drive allow fleets of starships to be built,
人类才开始探索星系
and mankind to start exploring the galaxy.
它以一种前所未有的办法 将人类统一了起来
It unites humanity in a way that no one ever thought possible.
人们认识到自己在宇宙中并不孤独
when they realize they're not alone in the universe.
贫穷 疾病 战争 这在50年后都会消失
Poverty, disease, war, they'll all be gone within the next 50 years.
可如果明天11点15分之前 你不进行曲翘飞行
But unless you make that warp flight tomorrow morning before 11:15,
这一切都不会发生
none of it will happen.
而你们都是太空人 在太空里漫游
And you people, you're all astronauts on some kind of star trek.
听着博士 我知道这些对你来说很难接受
Look, Doc, I know this is a lot for you to take in,
可我们没太多时间 我们需要你的帮助
but we're running out of time here. We need your help.
怎么样 博士？
What do you say?
有何不可？
Why not?
情况很糟糕 长官
It's pretty bad, sir.
他们已经控制了11层到26层
It looks like they control Decks 26 up to 11.
可是到了11层以后 他们呢就停住了
But when they took Deck 11, they just stopped.
博格人在几个小时内 同化了大半个船的人
The Borg have assimilated more than half the ship in a matter of hours.
为什么会停在那儿？11层都有什么？
Why stop there? What is on Deck 11?
水载植物 星际地图 偏正盘
Hydroponics, stellar cartography, deflector control.
- 都不是重要系统 - 我想肯定是因为那儿有什么战术优势
- No vital system. - They would not have stopped there.
他们才会停在那儿
unless it gave them a tactical advantage.
返回岗位
Return to your checkpoint.
- 每十分钟报告一次 - 是 长官
- Send reports every 10 minutes. - Right, sir.
医务室里肯定出了事
Something must've happened in Sickbay.
克拉什医生和其他人呢？
Where are Dr. Crusher and the others?
你们为什么违背停火协议？
Why did you break the cease-fire?
- 不是我们攻击你们！- 那是谁？
- We didn't attack you! - Who did?
有一个新组织
There's a new faction.
想要阻止你们明天上午的飞行
that wants to prevent your launch tomorrow morning,
可我们是来帮你们的
but we are here to help you.
这可能很难接受 可现在你已经不在蒙大拿了
This may be difficult for you to accept, but you are not in Montana anymore.
你在一艘环绕地球飞行的太空船上 高度…
You're on a ship, a spaceship orbiting the Earth at an altitude of…
你想帮我 那就带我离开
You wanna help me, get me out of here.
好吧
All right.
你想找出口 这就是
You want a way out. Here it is.
这是什么？
What is this?
澳大利亚 新几内亚 所罗门群岛
Australia, New Guinea, the Solomons.
蒙大拿很快就会出现 你可能得屏住呼吸
Montana will be up soon, but you may want to hold your breath.
这儿离地面很远
It's a long way down.
现在听我说 我不是你的敌人 我能带你回家
Now, listen to me. I'm not your enemy, and I can get you home,
可首先你得放下武器 相信我
but first you must put that weapon down and trust me.
吉恩·卢克·皮卡特
Jean-Luc Picard.
我的名字 那是我的名字 你的呢？
My name. That's my name. What's yours?
莉莉
Lily.
欢迎光临 莉莉
Welcome aboard, Lily.
谢谢
Thank you.
最大强度 你一开枪 我就会人间蒸发
Maximum setting. If you'd fired this, you would've vaporized me.
我第一次用这种枪
It's my first ray gun.
没有玻璃
There's no glass.
力场
Force field.
我从没见过这种技术
I've never seen that kind of technology.
那是因为它还没有被发明
That's because it hasn't been invented yet.
什么？
What?
要解释的太多了 过来
There's more I have to tell you. Come on.
你准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
- 你是谁？- 我就是博格
- Who are you? - I am the Borg.
这真是矛盾 博格人只有集体意识
That is a contradiction. The Borg have a collective consciousness.
他们没有个人
There are no individuals.
我既是开端又是终点 既是个人又是集体
I am the beginning, the end, the one who is many.
我就是博格
I am the Borg.
你好
Greetings.
我很好奇 是你在控制博格集体吗？
I am curious. Do you control the Borg collective?
你说的地位悬殊并不存在 我就是集体
You imply a disparity where none exists. I am the collective.
也许我该换个说法
Perhaps I should rephrase the question.
我非常想弄清楚你们的组织关系
I wish to understand the organizational relationships.
你是他们的领袖？
Are you their leader?
我可以化乱为治
I bring order to chaos.
很有趣的回答 虽然很隐晦
An interesting if cryptic response.
你正处于混乱中 数据
You are in chaos, Data.
你自身就是矛盾 一个想成为人的机器
You are the contradiction. A machine who wishes to be human.
既然你对我这么了解
Since you seem to know so much about me,
你就该知道我的程序设定就是进化 就是超越自我
you must be aware that I am programmed to evolve, to better myself.
我们也正在寻求自我
We, too, are on a quest to better ourselves,
向一种完美的境界进化
evolving toward a state of perfection.
坦白说 博格人不是进化 只是征服
Forgive me, but the Borg do not evolve. They conquer.
我们的集体把他们吸收进来
By assimilating other beings into our collective,
使他们更加接近完美
we are bringing them closer to perfection.
不知为什么 我觉得你的动机很可疑
Somehow, I question your motives.
那是因为你还没有受到
That is because you haven't been properly.
适当的刺激
stimulated yet.
你启动了我的情感芯片
You have reactivated my emotion chip.
- 为什么？- 你不必害怕
- Why? - Don't be frightened.
我没有害怕
I am not frightened.
知道这是什么吗 数据？
Do you know what this is, Data?
看来你是想把有机皮肤
It would appear you are attempting to graft organic skin.
移植到我的骨骼结构上
onto my endoskeletal structure.
如此美丽的礼物 却这样冰冷的描述它
What a cold description for such a beautiful gift.
感觉舒服吗？
Was that good for you?
联邦里有多少行星？
How many planets are in this Federation?
8000光年范围内的150颗行星
Over 150, spread across 8, 000 light-years.
你肯定很少回家
You must not get home much.
事实上 这艘船就是我的家
Actually, I tend to think of this ship as home.
如果你是指地球 只要有机会我就会回去
But if it's Earth you're talking about, I try to get back whenever I can.
很好 他们还没有破解密码
Good. They haven't broken the encryption codes yet.
谁 你说的那些骷髅人？
Who, those bionic zombies you told me about?
- 博格人 - 博格？很像瑞典名字
- Borg. - Borg? Sounds Swedish.
- 这艘船有多大？- 共有24层
- How big is this ship? - There are 24 decks,
大概700米长
almost 700 meters long.
我花六个月的时间收集到的钛
It took me six months to scrounge up enough titanium.
才能建一个4米的座舱
just to build a four-meter cockpit.
这得花多少钱啊？
How much did this thing cost?
未来的经济有点不太一样
The economics of the future are somewhat different.
知道吗 24世纪已经不存在金钱了
You see, money doesn't exist in the 24th century.
没有钱？你是说你们没有工资？
No money? You mean you don't get paid?
获取财富不再是我们的生活劳动
The acquisition of wealth is no longer the driving force in our lives.
我们工作是为了改进自我还有整个人类
We work to better ourselves and the rest of humanity.
事实上 有点像你和科克伦博士
Actually, we're rather like yourself and Dr. Cochrane.
别叫！没事！
All right! All right!
- 过来 - 没有其他路了吗？
- Come on. - Is there another way around?
别紧张 听我的
I know what I'm doing.
绝对不是瑞典人
Definitely not Swedish.
你在搞什么鬼？
What the hell are you doing?
给你来件绸缎衣服？
Perhaps something in satin?
对不起 先生们 我们已经打烊了
I'm sorry, gentlemen, but we're closing.
而且我们对着装有严格的要求
And you do understand we have a strict dress code,
如果你们不马上离开我就…
so if you boys don't leave right now, I'll…
我想找大鼻子尼基
I'm looking for Nicky the Nose.
大鼻子？他好几个月没来了
The Nose? He hasn't been here in months.
看来不是这一章
This is the wrong chapter.
电脑！快给我进入第13章
Computer! Begin chapter 13.
装作很开心的样子
Try and look as if you're having a good time.
不 不 不 看着我！表现的自然一点儿
No, no, no, look at me! Try to act naturally.
他在那儿
There he is.
露碧 现在不太方便
Ruby, this is not a good time.
你总是不太方便 对吧 迪克斯？总是有借口
It's never the time for us, is it, Dix? Always some excuse,
- 总是有什么案子 - 我有事找尼基 待会儿见
- some case you're working on. - I have to talk to Nicky. I'll see you later.
好吧 千万要小心
Okay, but watch your caboose.
甩掉这女人
And dump the broad.
哇 哇 哇 看看这是谁来了
Well, well, well. Look what the cat dragged in.
最近怎么样 迪克斯？
What's shaking, Dix?
老样子 尼克 喝酒玩女人 对不起
The usual, Nick. Martinis and skirts. Excuse me.
嘿 我会跟你算这笔账的
Hey, I'm going to take that personal in a second.
请别见怪
No offense.
嘿！
Hey!
我想他已经死了
I think you got him.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你不是说 这只是全息图吗
I thought you said this was all just a bunch of holograms.
- 如果是全息图的话… - 我解除了安全协议
- If it's holograms… - I disengaged the safety protocols.
这样的话 就算是全息子弹也能杀人
Without them, even a holographic bullet can kill.
- 你在干什么？- 我在找神经处理期
- What are you doing? - I'm looking for the neuroprocessor.
每个博格人都有 就像是记忆芯片
Every Borg has one. It's like a memory chip.
上面记载着这个博格人
It will contain a record of all the instructions.
从集体接到的所有命令
This Borg has been receiving from the collective.
哦 天啊 吉恩·卢克 那是你们的制服
Oh, my. Jean-Luc, it's one of your uniforms.
对 他是 英吉少尉
Yes, this was Ensign Lynch.
运气够糟的 哈？
Tough luck, huh?
我们得到舰桥去
I've gotta get to the Bridge.
早上好
Good morning, sir.
博士？
Doctor?
- 什么？- 能看一下这个吗？
- Yeah? - Would you mind taking a look at this?
好
Yeah.
我想凭着上学时的印象
I tried to reconstruct the intermix chamber.
重建混合室
from what I remember in school.
你看对不对
Tell me if I got it right.
学校？
School?
- 你在学校学过这个？- 哦 对
- You learned about this in school? - Oh, yeah.
基本曲翘设计是大学的必修课程
Basic Warp Design is a required course at the Academy.
第一章就叫做「泽弗兰·科克伦」
The first chapter is called "Zefram Cochrane".
嗯 看上去没问题
Well, it looks like you got it right.
中校 我们打算用这个来代替
Commander, this is what we're thinking of using.
被损坏的曲翘等离子管道
to replace the damaged warp plasma conduit.
好 瑞吉 非常不错
Yeah, Reg. Yeah, that's good,
不过你需要同毫微聚合物把它加固一下
but you need to reinforce this copper tubing with a nanopolymer.
科克伦博士 我知道这样很傻 我能跟您握个手吗？
Dr. Cochrane, I know this sounds silly, but can I shake your hand?
谢谢你 博士
Thank you, Doctor.
能跟你一起工作真是天大的荣幸
I can't tell you what an honor it is to work with you on this project.
- 瑞吉 - 我从来没有想过能跟
- Reg. - I never imagined that I'd be meeting.
- 曲翘推进器的发明人 我… - 瑞吉！
- the man who invented warp drive. I… - Reg!
对不起 嗯 谢谢
I'm sorry. Right. Thanks.
他们非得这样吗？
Do they have to keep doing that?
只是一点点英雄崇拜 博士
It's just a little hero worship, Doc.
说句实在话 这也难怪他们
To tell you the truth, I can't say I blame them.
我们都是听着你从前的事迹长大的
We all grew up hearing about what you did here.
或者说以后的事情
Or what you're about to do.
知道吗 也许我不该跟您说这个
You know, I probably shouldn't even tell you this,
我上的是泽弗兰·科克伦高中
but I went to Zefram Cochrane High School.
真的？
Really?
知道吗 我真的希望能跟你拍张照片
You know, I wish I had a picture of this.
- 什么？- 哦 告诉你
- What? - Well, you see,
以后这儿整个地方都会成为历史的遗迹
in the future, this whole area becomes an historical monument.
差不多您站的那个地方
You're standing almost on the exact spot.
就会竖起您的雕像
where your statue's gonna be.
- 雕像？- 哦 对！
- Statue? - Oh, yeah!
它是用大理石雕的 20米高 你抬头仰望着天空
It's marble, about 20 meters tall, and you're looking up at the sky,
一只手向前伸向未来
and your hand's sort of reaching toward the future.
我要去放水
I gotta take a leak.
放水？什么地方漏水了
Leak? I'm not detecting any leak.
难道24世纪的人就不用撒尿吗？
Don't you people from the 24th century ever pee?
放水！明白了
Leak! I get it.
真有意思
That's pretty funny.
失陪了
Excuse me.
中校？
Commander?
- 船长 - 吉恩·卢克
- Captain. - Jean-Luc.
我被同化的谣言纯属无中生有
Reports of my assimilation are greatly exaggerated.
我找到了你的失物
I found something you lost.
- 我是克林冈人 - 沃尔夫 报告情况
- I am a Klingon. - Mr. Worf, report.
博格人控制了大半艘船
The Borg control over half the ship.
我们试着恢复舰桥和武器系统的动力
We have tried to restore power to the Bridge and the weapon systems,
- 可是失败了 - 还有一个麻烦
- but we have been unsuccessful. - We have another problem.
我在博格人的神经处理器里
I've accessed a Borg neuroprocessor,
发现了他们的目的
and I've discovered what they're trying to do.
他们在把偏转盘改装成为信标发射台
They're transforming the deflector dish into an interplexing beacon.
信标发射台？
Interplexing?
一种子空间发射器 如果他们启动了发射器
It's a subspace transmitter. If they activate the beacon,
他们就能和这个世纪的博格人取得联系
they'll be able to establish a link with the Borg living in this century.
可在21世纪博格人还住在三角洲区
But in the 21st century, the Borg are still in the Delta Quadrant.
他们会派援兵过来攻击人类就会易如反掌
They'll send reinforcements. Humanity will be an easy target.
攻击过去 同化未来
Attack the Earth in the past to assimilate the future.
那就要在启动发射器前摧毁偏转盘
Then we must destroy the deflector dish before they can activate the beacon.
我们无法控制偏转盘或是宇宙渡船…
We can't get to deflector control or a shuttlecraft…
沃尔夫先生你还记得无重力格斗训练吗？
Mr. Worf, do you remember your zero- g combat training?
我记得我恶心的想吐
I remember it made me sick to my stomach.
你有什么建议？
What are you suggesting?
我想我们应该出去散散步了
I think it's time that we took a little stroll.
等等 前面有人类生命
Hang on. There's a humanoid life-sign up ahead.
511米远
Five hundred eleven meters.
科克伦？
Cochrane?
就是他
It's him, all right.
我调整了激光桥的频率
I've re-modulated the pulse emitters,
但是我想 只要开一两枪
but I do not believe we will get more than one or two shots.
- 博格人就会完全适应的 - 那我们就得一枪一个
- before the Borg adapt. - Then we must make every shot count.
启动磁力
Magnetize.
- 千万要小心 迪克斯 - 我会的
- Watch your caboose, Dix. - I intend to.
- 感觉怎么样 沃尔夫？- 不太好 长官
- How are you doing, Mr. Worf? - Not well, sir.
不要看着那些星星 眼睛盯着船身
Try not to look at the stars. Keep your eyes on the hull.
出发
Let's go.
告诉我 你是不是通过聚合体神经传输器
Tell me, are you using a polymer-based neuro-relay.
将有机神经脉冲发送到
to transmit the organic nerve impulses.
我的正电子网络中央处理器上呢？
to the central processor of my positronic net?
如果是这样的话
If that is the case,
你是如何解决有机合成金属
how have you solved the problem of increased signal degradation.
固有的信号逐渐减弱这些问题
inherent to organo-ynthetic transmission…
你总是这么多话吗？
Do you always talk this much?
不是总是 只是经常
Not always, but often.
你为什么坚持使用这种原始的语言进行交流
Why do you insist on utilizing this primitive linguistic communication?
你的机器大脑实在是大才小用了
Your android brain is capable of so much more.
难道你忘了 我努力的想变的更像人类
Have you forgotten? I am endeavoring to become more human.
人类 我们以前和他们很像 有缺陷 软弱的有机生物
Human. We used to be exactly like them. Flawed, weak,
可是我们在进化时加进了合成物质
But we evolved to include the synthetic.
我们把这两点结合起来寻求完美
Now we use both to attain perfection.
你的目标应该和我们是一致的
Your goal should be the same as ours.
像你这样自认为完美通常是精神错乱的先兆
Believing oneself to be perfect is often the sign of a delusional mind.
你这井底之蛙
Small words from a small being.
对自己不明白的事情竟敢妄加评论
trying to attack what he doesn't understand.
我明白 你对我没有真真的兴趣
I understand that you have no real interest in me,
其实你的目的只是想
that your goal is to obtain the encryption codes.
拿到企业号的电脑密码
for the Enterprise computer.
这只是目的之一 众多目的中的一个
That is one of our goals, one of many.
为此 我愿意帮助你达到你的目的
But in order to reach it, I am willing to help you reach yours.
你开始弄明白了吗？
Is it becoming clear to you yet?
看看你自己吧
Look at yourself, standing there,
那么爱护我送给你的肉体
cradling the new flesh that I've given you.
如果它对你没有意义 干嘛要保护它？
If it means nothing to you, why protect it?
我 我只是在模仿人类的行为
I am simply imitating the behavior of humans.
你是越来越像人类了 数据
You're becoming more human all the time, Data.
现在居然还学会了撒谎
Now you're learning how to lie.
我的程序它不知道该怎么处理这些感觉
My programming was not designed to process these sensations.
那就把它当成故障电路给扯下来不就行了
Then tear the skin from your limb as you would a defective circuit.
动手啊 数据 我不会拦着你的
Go ahead, Data. We won't stop you.
动手吧 不要被肉体诱惑
Do it. Don't be tempted by flesh.
你体验过肉体上的愉悦感吗？
Are you familiar with physical forms of pleasure?
如果 你现在指的是性能力的话
If you are referring to sexuality,
我没有任何问题
I am fully functional,
我的程序设有多种技巧
programmed in multiple techniques.
多久没有使用这些技巧了？
How long has it been since you've used them?
8年
Eight years,
零7个月16天4分钟22秒…
seven months, 16 days, four minutes, 22…
太久了
Far too long.
- 我们该多叫点人来 - 来不及了
- We should bring reinforcements. - There's no time.
看来他们在把信标建在粒子发射器上
It looks as if they're building the beacon right on top of the particle emitter.
只要所有的收发器杆放置到位
Once all the transponder rods are in place,
信标就会被启动
the beacon will be activated.
把死光枪调到最大强度怎么样…
Well, if we set our phasers to full power, we can…
不 那可能会击中偏转盘 上面全是反质子
No. There's a risk that we hit the dish. It's charged with antiprotons.
会毁掉半艘船 得想点儿别的办法
We could destroy half the ship. We have to find another way.
快 快
Come on, come on.
- 博士！- 长官？
- Doctor! - Sir?
你还在找厕所吗？
You still looking for the bathroom?
- 我不要回去 - 听着 博士 没有你我们没法成功
- I'm not going back. - Look, Doc, we can't do this without you.
我不管 我不想成为雕像
I don't care. I don't wanna be a statue.
- 博士… - 你们不要过来
- Doctor… - You stay away from me.
没时间跟他耗了
We don't have time for this.
你跟他说了雕像的事？
You told him about the statue?
要想成功 三个磁锁都得打开才行
For this to work, all three maglocks will have to be released.
电磁压缩器分离
Magnetic constrictors are disengaged.
他们适应了
They've adapted.
警告 45秒后还原
Warning. Decompression in 45 seconds.
霍克！
Hawk!
我们的计划有变 数据
We've had a change of plans, Data.
同化这一枪吧
Assimilate this.
还有一个小时 你感觉怎么样？
Only got an hour to go, Doc. How you feeling?
头疼的要死
I got a four-alarm hangover,
要么因为威士忌 要么因为你那枪 要么都有
either from the whiskey or your laser beam, or both,
不过我已经准备好了
but I'm ready to make history.
- 特洛伊呼叫瑞克中校 - 请讲
- Troi to Commander Riker. - Riker here.
- 我们准备大开发射门 - 打开吧
- We're ready to open the launch door. - Go ahead.
看那个
Look at that.
怎么 24世纪没有月亮？
What, you don't have a moon in the 24th century?
当然有 不过看上去很不一样
Sure we do. It just looks a lot different.
那时月亮上住了5000万人口
There are 50 million people living on the moon in my time.
天晴时能看见 蒂古市 新柏林甚至还有阿姆斯特朗湖
You can see Tycho City, New Berlin, even Lake Armstrong on a day like this.
- 知道吗 博士… - 拜托！
- And you know, Doctor… - Please!
别告诉我这都归功于我
Don't tell me it's all thanks to me.
泽弗兰·科克伦的丰功伟绩我已经听够了
I've heard enough about the great Zefram Cochrane.
不知道你们的历史是谁编的
I don't know who writes your history books.
你们的历史是哪来的
or where you get your information from,
不过你们的人对我的看法太好笑了
but you people got some pretty funny ideas about me.
你们都把我看成一种圣人或思想家什么的
You all look at me as if I'm some kind of saint or visionary or something.
我不认为你是圣人 博士 但你确实很有理想
I don't think you're a saint, Doc, but you did have a vision.
这艘船就是证据
And now we're sitting in it.
知道我的理想是什么吗？
You wanna know what my vision is?
美元 是钱
Dollar signs. Money.
我造这艘船不是为了开创人类的新时代
I didn't build this ship to usher in a new era for humanity.
你以为我想上天？我甚至都不喜欢飞！我甚至都坐火车！
You think I want to go to the stars? I don't even like to fly! I take trains!
我造这艘飞船是为了退休以后能去热带岛屿
I built this ship so that I could retire to some tropical island.
岛上全是裸体女人
filled with naked women.
这才是泽弗兰·科克伦 这才是他的理想
That's Zefram Cochrane. That's his vision.
你们说个没完的这家伙 这个历史人物
This other guy you keep talking about, this historical figure,
我没见过他
I never met him.
以后大概也见不到
I can't imagine I ever will.
有人曾今说过「不求立大功 但求尽几责」
Someone once said, "Don't try to be a great man. Just be a man, "
「成败历史自有定论」
"and let history make its own judgments."
冠冕堂皇的废话
That's rhetorical nonsense.
- 谁说的？- 你说的 十年后说的
- Who said that? - You did, 10 years from now.
还有58分钟 博士 你最好开始进行检查
You got 58 minutes, Doc. You better get on that checklist.
博格人又行动了
They're on the move again.
他们刚刚占领了我们三个防御点
The Borg just overran three of our defense checkpoints.
占领了5层和6层
They've taken over Decks 5 and 6.
他们已经适应了我们所有武器
They've adapted to every modulation of our weapons.
现在就像对空气开枪一样
It's like we're shooting blanks.
我们在想办法改进武器
We'll have to work on finding another way.
增加杀伤力
to modify our weapons so they'll be more effective.
记住让你的人坚守阵地
In the meantime, tell your men to stand their ground.
- 长官… - 必要的时候就进行肉搏
- Sir… - Fight hand-to-hand if they have to.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
等等 船长 武器已经失效了
Wait. Captain, our weapons are useless.
我们必须启动自动摧毁程序
We must activate the auto- destruct sequence.
利用逃生舱撤离飞船
and use the escape pods to evacuate the ship.
不！
No!
吉恩·卢克 毁掉这艘船等于摧毁博格人
Jean-Luc, if we destroy the ship, we destroy the Borg.
我们要战斗到底
We're gonna stay and fight.
长官 我们已经失去了企业号 我们不应该无谓牺牲了…
Sir, we have lost the Enterprise. We should not sacrifice…
我们没有失去企业号 沃尔夫
We have not lost the Enterprise, Mr. Worf.
我也不会让博格人你得到企业号
We are not going to lose the Enterprise.
只要有我在
Not to the Borg, not while I'm in command.
- 这是命令 - 我必须反对这种决定
- You have your orders. - I must object to this course of action.
- 我们应该… - 你的意见我知道了
- It is… - The objection is noted.
恕我直言 长官
With all due respect, sir,
我认为你是在让你跟博格人的亲身经历
I believe you are allowing your personal experience with the Borg.
影响你的判断力
to influence your judgment.
你害怕了
You're afraid.
你想摧毁飞船然后逃走 你这懦夫
You want to destroy the ship and run away. You coward.
吉恩·卢克
Jean-Luc.
如果你是别人的话 我会当场杀了你
If you were any other man, I would kill you where you stand.
离开我的舰桥
Get off my Bridge.
- 现在怎么办？- 执行他的命令
- So what do we do now? - We carry out his orders.
戴森 卡普兰
Dyson, Kaplan,
- 你们负责… - 等等！
- start working on a way to modify… - Wait!
- 对武器系统进行改进 - 这太愚蠢了！
- the weapon systems. - This is stupid!
如果能够离开这艘船再摧毁他 为什么不这么做！
If we can get off this ship and then blow it up, let's do it!
船长下定决心就不可能改变
Once the Captain's made up his mind, the discussion is over.
莉莉！
Lily!
- 你这个混蛋 - 现在不是吵架的时候
- You son of a bitch. - This really isn't the time.
好吧 我对24世纪一无所知
Okay, I don't know jack about the 24th century,
可外面每个人都认为死守这艘船
but everybody out there thinks that staying here.
形同自杀
and fighting the Borg is suicide.
他们只是不敢进来跟你说
They're just afraid to come in here and say it.
船员们习惯服从我的命令
The crew is accustomed to following my orders.
他们可能只是习惯于你的合理命令
They're probably accustomed to your orders making sense.
谁也不如我了解博格人
None of them understand the Borg as I do.
没有人
No one does.
没人能
No one can.
你这话是什么意思？
What is that supposed to mean?
六年前 他们把我同化进了他们的集体
Six years ago, they assimilated me into their collective.
我全身都植入了他们的自动化装置
I had their cybernetic devices implanted throughout my body.
我和集体相连 所有的个性都被抹去
I was linked to the hive mind, every trace of individuality erased.
我成了他们一员
I was one of them.
所以你应该明白
So you can imagine, my dear,
我能够知道博格人的打算
I have a somewhat unique perspective on the Borg,
我知道怎么对付他们
and I know how to fight them.
如果你不介意 我还有工作要做
Now, if you will excuse me, I have work to do.
我真是个白痴
I am such an idiot.
多简单啊
It's so simple.
博格人伤害了你 现在你要报复回去
The Borg hurt you, and now you're going to hurt them back.
在我的年代 我们不谈报复
In my century, we don't succumb to revenge.
我们的理智比这要先进的多
We have a more evolved sensibility.
胡说！我看到过
Bullshit! I saw the look on your face.
你杀死博格人时的表情
when you shot those Borg on the Holodeck.
你几乎是在享受！
You were almost enjoying it!
- 胡言乱语 - 哦 拜托 船长
- How dare you. - Oh, come on, Captain.
你并不是第一个从杀人中得到快感的人
You're not the first man to get a thrill from murdering someone.
这样的人我见的多了！
I see it all the time!
- 滚出去！- 不然呢？
- Get out! - Or what?
你会杀了我 就像杀了英吉少尉那样？
You'll kill me like you killed Ensign Lynch?
- 没有办法可以救他 - 你连试都没试过
- There was no way to save him. - You didn't even try.
你的先进理智去哪了？
Where was your evolved sensibility then?
- 我没时间跟你吵 - 哦
- I don't have time for this. - Hey.
对不起 我不想打扰你追捕猎物
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to interrupt your little quest.
亚哈船长必须捕捉他的鲸鱼
Captain Ahab has to go hunt his whale.
什么？
What?
你们24世纪有书吗？
You do have books in the 24th century?
- 这不是为了报复 - 撒谎！
- This is not about revenge. - Liar!
这是为了拯救人类的未来！
This is about saving the future of humanity!
- 吉恩·卢克 炸掉这艘船！- 不！
- Jean-Luc, blow up the damn ship! - No!
不！
No!
我不会牺牲企业号
I will not sacrifice the Enterprise.
我们已经做了太多的妥协 太多的让步
We've made too many compromises already, too many retreats.
他们入侵太空 我们退让了
They invade our space and we fall back.
他们同化整个世界 我们也退让了
They assimilate entire worlds and we fall back.
够了
Not again.
这是最后的底线 绝不再退半步！
The line must be drawn here. This far, no further!
他们应该付出他们该付的代价
And I will make them pay for what they've done.
你打坏了你的小船
You broke your little ships.
再见 亚哈
See you around, Ahab.
「他们整个种族对鲸鱼的仇恨」
"And he piled upon the whale's white hump"
「都堆积在鲸鱼的背脊上」
"the sum of all the rage and hate felt by his whole race"
「如果他的胸膛是大炮 他会用心脏做弹药」.
"If his chest had been a cannon, he would have shot his heart upon it".
什么？
What?
白鲸记
Moby-Dick.
事实上 我从没看过
Actually, I never read it.
亚哈花了好几年时间去追捕那头使他残废的鲸鱼
Ahab spent years hunting the white whale that crippled him,
为了报复
a quest for vengeance,
可是到了最后 报复却使他人船俱毁
but in the end, it destroyed him and his ship.
他不懂什么时候该放手
I guess he didn't know when to quit.
准备撤离企业号
Prepare to evacuate the Enterprise.
- ATR 装置？- 启动了
- ATR setting? - Active.
- 主线路？- 就绪
- Main bus? - Ready.
启动点火前程序
Initiate pre-ignition sequence.
开始自动摧毁程序 授权 皮卡特4-7-α-T
Begin auto-destruct sequence. Authorization, Picard 4-7-alpha-tango.
电脑 贝弗利 克拉什中校
Computer, Commander Beverly Crusher.
确认自动摧毁程序 授权 克拉什2-2-β-c
Confirm auto-destruct sequence. Authorization, Crusher 2-2-beta-charlie.
电脑 沃尔夫少校
Computer, Lieutenant Commander Worf.
确认自动摧毁程序 授权 沃尔夫3-7-γ-e
Confirm auto-destruct sequence. Authorization, Worf 3-7-gamma-echo.
认可指挥授权
Command authorization accepted.
等待最终密码 开始自动摧毁程序
Awaiting final code to begin auto-destruct sequence.
我是船长 吉恩·卢克·皮卡特
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
自动摧毁程序α-1 十五分钟 无声倒计时
Destruct sequence alpha-one. Fifteen minutes, silent countdown.
启动
Enable.
15分钟后自动摧毁 不再有进一步的提示
Self-destruct in 15 minutes. There will be no further audio warnings.
企业E号结束了
So much for the Enterprise-E.
时间太短了
We barely knew her.
他们还会再造一艘吗？
Think they'll build another one?
我们还有很多字母可用
Plenty of letters left in the alphabet.
沃尔夫先生
Mr. Worf.
我对先前对你说过的一些话表示非常抱歉
I regret some of the things I said to you earlier.
什么话？
Some?
我想告诉你
As a matter of fact,
你是我见过的最勇敢的人
I think you're the bravest man I've ever known.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
格拉维特岛上见
See you on Gravett Island.
船长
Captain.
数据？
Data?
控制台呼叫凤凰号 最后检查已经完成
Control to Phoenix. Final launch sequence checks are complete.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
- 准备好创造历史了吗？- 早就好了
- Everybody ready to make some history? - Always am.
- 我好想忘了什么东西 - 什么？
- I think I forgot something. - What?
我不知道 可能没什么
I don't know. It's probably nothing.
开始点火程序
Begin ignition sequence.
- 20 19… - 哦 天啊！
- 20, 19… - Oh, God!
- 我想起来了！- 什么？
- Now I remember! - What?
- 在哪呢？- 什么？
- Where is it? - What?
- 没有它我没法发射！- 佐迪 我们得放弃
- We can't lift off without it! - Geordi, we've got to abort.
不！不 等等 我找到了
No! No, wait, I found it.
- 我爱摇滚乐！- 7 6…
- Let's rock and roll! - 7, 6…
能小点声吗？
Turn that down a little?
嘿！第二个进气阀亮着红灯呢
Hey! We've got a red light on the second intake valve.
别管它 没事儿的
Ignore it. We'll be fine.
听我指挥 进行第一阶段关闭和脱离
Prepare first stage shutdown and separation on my mark.
开始！
mark!
好了 启动曲翘推进器
Okay, let's bring the warp core online.
更美的在后面呢
You ain't seen nothing yet.
如果看到瑞克中校他们 把这个给他们
If you see Commander Riker or any of my crew, give them this.
这是什么？
What is it?
命令他们在北美找一个安静的角落
Orders to find a quiet corner of North America.
不要干扰历史的进程
and stay out of history's way.
好 祝你好运
Well, good luck.
祝我们两个
To both of us.
你是说你不走？
You're not leaving, are you?
莉莉 我被关在博格人的船上时
Lily, when I was held captive on the Borg ship,
我的船员们冒着危险去救我
my crew risked everything to save me.
现在
There is.
还有一名船员
someone.
被困在船上
still on this ship,
我必须去救他
and I owe him the same.
去找你的朋友吧
Go and find your friend.
怎么了 卢丘塔斯？这一切不熟悉吗？
What's wrong, Locutus? Isn't this familiar?
有机意识是这么脆弱的东西
Organic minds are such fragile things.
你怎么能这么快就把我忘了？
How could you forget me so quickly?
我们曾经那么亲近 你和我
We were very close, you and I.
你仍然能听到我的声音
You can still hear our song.
对 我…
Yes, I…
记起来了
I remember you.
你一直都在那儿
You were there all the time.
可是那艘船
But that ship.
和船上的博格人都被炸毁了
and all the Borg on it were destroyed.
你的想法是这么的三维
You think in such three-dimensional terms.
你变的很渺小
How small you've become.
数据就能明白我
Data understands me.
对吧 数据？
Don't you, Data?
你对他做了什么？
What have you done to him?
他一直想要的血肉之躯
Given him what he always wanted, flesh and blood.
放他走 他不是你要的人
Let him go. He's not the one you want.
你是在向我献身吗？
Are you offering yourself to us?
向你献身？
Offering myself?
对 没错 我想起来了
That's it. I remember now.
你同化了我还觉得不够
It wasn't enough that you assimilate me.
我要把自己完全献给博格
I had to give myself freely to the Borg.
- 给你 - 你太高估自己了
- To you. - You flatter yourself.
我同化过几百万个人
I've overseen the assimilation of countless millions.
- 你没有什么不同 - 你撒谎
- You were no different. - You're lying.
你要的不仅仅是一个博格雄蜂
You wanted more than just another Borg drone.
你要的是一个有自己意识的人类
You wanted a human being with a mind of his own.
他能在人类和博格人之间架起桥梁
who could bridge the gulf between humanity and the Borg.
你要的是搭档
You wanted a counterpart.
可我拒绝了
But I resisted.
我反抗了
I fought you.
你甚至都不知道自己拒绝了多好的机会
You can't begin to imagine the life you denied yourself.
现在还不迟
It's not too late.
卢丘塔斯还可以在你身边 就像你想要的那样
Locutus could still be with you, just in the way you wanted,
一个对等体
an equal.
放了数据 我就会自愿的站在你身边
Let Data go, and I will take my place at your side,
不做任何反抗
willingly, without any resistance.
多么高尚的情操
Such a noble creature,
我们就缺乏这种品质
a quality we sometimes lack.
我们会吸收你的优点
We will add your distinctiveness to our own.
欢迎你回来 卢丘塔斯
Welcome home, Locutus.
数据 你可以走
Data, you are free to go.
- 数据 快走 - 不
- Data, go. - No.
我不想走
I do not wish to go.
你都看到了 我已经找到了一个对等体
As you can see, I have already found an equal.
数据 关闭飞船的自动摧毁程序
Data, deactivate the self- destruct sequence.
数据 不 不要这么做
Data, no. Don't do it.
数据 听我说
Data, listen to me.
自动摧毁程序关闭
Auto-destruct sequence deactivated.
输入密码 把电脑的控制权给我
Now enter the encryption codes and give me computer control.
数据！
Data!
数据
Data.
他会是匹出色的种马
He will make an excellent drone.
等离子喷射器已经启动 一切看上去都很好
Plasma injectors are online. Everything's looking good.
一切就绪
I think we're ready.
他们应该就在那儿
They should be out there right now.
要想引起他们的注意 5分钟内
We better break the warp barrier in the next five minutes.
就得进入曲翘速度
if we're gonna get their attention.
- 已经加足马力 准备就绪 - 开始吧！
- Nacelles are charged and ready. - Let's do it!
出发！
Engage!
曲翘场情况良好
Warp field is looking good.
飞船的结构很稳定
Structural integrity is holding.
- 速度？- 每秒两万公里
- Speed? - 20, 000 kilometers per second.
我的老天爷啊！
Sweet Jesus!
放松 博士 他们肯定是来送行的
Relax, Doctor. I'm sure they're just here to give us a send-off.
我已经启动了外部传感器
I am bringing the external sensors online.
30秒后进入曲翘速度
Thirty seconds to warp threshold.
正在接近光速
Approaching light-speed.
现在是临界速度
We're at critical velocity.
- 量子鱼雷已经锁定目标 - 摧毁他们
- Quantum torpedoes locked. - Destroy them.
看着 你的未来完蛋了
Watch your future's end.
数据！
Data!
没有未来的
Resistance is futile.
应该是你们
That should be enough. Throttle back. Take us out of warp.
那个是地球？
Is that Earth?
没错
That's it.
这么小
It's so small.
马上就会变得很大
It's about to get a whole lot bigger.
船长
Captain.
数据
Data.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我猜我看上去一定非常的…
I would imagine I look worse than I…
糟糕
feel.
真的很奇怪
Strange.
我居然因为她的死而感到有些难过
Part of me is sorry she is dead.
她很特别
She was unique.
她让我和人类有了从未有过的接近
She brought me closer to humanity than I ever thought possible,
有那么一会儿
and for a time,
我真的被她所打动了
I was tempted by her offer.
一会儿是多久？
How long a time?
一共是0.68秒 长官
Zero-point-six-eight seconds, sir.
可对机器人来说 这已经接近于永恒
For an android, that is nearly an eternity.
船长日志 2063年4月5日
Captain's Log, April 5th, 2063.
凤凰号的航空旅行成功了
The voyage of the Phoenix was a success,
外星飞船捕捉到了曲翘信号
The alien ship detected the warp signature.
正在前来做历史性的会面
and is on its way to rendezvous with history.
天啊
My God.
他们真的来自另一个世界
They're really from another world.
他们想见见曲翘飞船的驾驶员
And they're going to want to meet the man who flew that warp ship.
祝健康长寿
Live long and prosper.
谢谢
Thanks.
我想 我们该悄然隐退了
I think it's time we made a discreet exit.
瑞克呼叫企业号 准备传送
Riker to Enterprise, stand by to beam us up.
你要走了？
You gotta go?
我羡慕你们
I envy you,
你们要去的世界
the world you're going to.
我也羡慕你
I envy you,
羡慕你率先开拓新领域
taking these first steps into a new frontier.
我会想你的 莉莉
I shall miss you, Lily.
皮卡特呼叫企业号 传送
Picard to Enterprise. Energize.
- 报告情况 - 月亮的引力场掩盖了我们的曲翘信号
- Report. - The moon's gravitational field.
沃尔坎人没发现我们
obscured our warp signature. The Vulcans did not detect us.
船长 我重配了曲翘场
Captain, I've reconfigured our warp field.
来配合博格区的计时读数
to match the chronometric readings of the Borg sphere.
- 重新造出时间旋涡 中校 - 是 长官
- Recreate the vortex, Commander. - Aye, sir.
各层准备完毕
All decks report ready.
- 舵手正在待命 - 数据
- Helm standing by. - Mr. Data,
设定回24世纪的航线
lay in a course for the 24th century.
我想我们的未来正在等待着我们
I suspect our future is there waiting for us.
航线设定完毕 长官
Course laid in, sir.
前进吧
Make it so.
不 不 我给你放段好听的
No, no, I give you some music.
不 不！别走！你听听 不错的！
No no! Don't go! Enjoy it!
跳起来啊 伙计们
Let's dance, guys.